Thundercats - S01E10
霹雳猫 第一季 第十集
视界之上
Now we're cooking.
我们快到了
Book says the stone is dead ahead.
书上显示石头就在前方
Then how about getting this
hunk of junk moving, Panthro?
不能让这个大家伙再开快点吗，猛猫？
I'm not about to blow up the samoflange
again just as you got no patience
我可不想因为你的急性子再把车子搞坏
Slow and steady wins the race, kid.
比赛中慢而稳才是最重要的
Race? Now that's an idea.
比赛？这是个好主意
You're on.
那就来吧
You sure you want to
embarrass yourself, Tygra?
你确实要跟我比，虎猫？
You've never beaten me
at anything in your life.
你还从没在任何方面赢过我呢
On three then.
那就看着吧
1...2...
- Whoa
- Ho!
-哇哦
-呼！
3.
They're beating us.
他们超过我们了
They're not beating us
because we're not racing.
我们又有没在比赛
What Panthro is trying to say, kids,
猛猫想说的是
is that he doesn't mind losing.
他不会在意输掉比赛
Hold on. It's about to get bumpy.
坐稳了，马上就会有些颠簸
- Aah!
- Ow!
- Faster! Faster!
-再快点！再快点！
It's looking like slow and steady
看起来慢而稳
doesn't win the race.
是赢不了这场比赛的
Where are you going?
你要去哪?
To give these boys
some real competition.
让那些小子们见识一下什么叫真正的比赛
You want to see fast?
你想看看谁更快？
Got my baby hummin' now.
Listen to her purr.
该我的宝贝上场了
听听机器震颤吧
Will this make us go faster?
按这个能让车跑得更快吗？
Don't touch that! [beeps]
别按那个
- Uh, she did it.
- Uh-uh-uh.
-是她干的
-呃
Incoming!
导弹袭来了！
That's cheating.
那不算数！
Winner and still champion.
这次还是我赢了
Check this out.
看看这个
Everything's so big.
每样东西都好大
Including the residents.
这里的居民也是.
Excuse me.
打扰一下
Hello!
你好！
- Hmm?
- Huh?
-嗯？
- What?
- What is it?
-怎么了？
-谁来了？
- Huh?
- What?
Heh. Sorry.
呃，抱歉
I am Lion-O, Lord of the Thundercats.
我是狮猫，霹雳猫的国王
I am Aburn.
我是Aburn
And you are...?
请问你是...？
Uh, name's Lion-O...
呃，我叫狮猫
Lord of the Thundercats.
霹雳猫的国王
Welcome, Lion-El.
欢迎你，湿猫
Lion-O.
是狮猫
How can we assist you?
有什么需要我们帮忙的吗？
We're looking for a magical stone.
我们在寻找一块魔法石
We believe it's
somewhere in your village.
我们觉得它应该就在你们的村庄里
What is?
什么？
Kind of forgetful, isn't he?
他好像有点健忘，不是吗？
I think he's cute.
我觉得他蛮可爱的
Listen, Aburn, we're searching
for a stone that looks like this.
是这样的，我们在寻找一块像这样的石头
When did you lose it?
你们什么时候把它弄丢的？
We didn't lose it.
我们没弄丢
So you have it?
那你们已经得到那块石头了？
No, we're looking for it.
不，我们正在找它
And what is it exactly
you are looking for?
那你们在找什么呢？
Oh, you've got to be kidding me.
哦，他一定是在开玩笑吧
I can't remember the last
time I saw a cat in these parts.
我都想不起来上次在这里看到猫是什么时候的事了
Yes, Anet. They
are looking for--
没错，Anet，他们在寻找--
uh, what were you looking for, Lion-Lord?
呃，你们在找什么来着？
- The stone!
-魔法石！
If it is the spirit stone you seek,
如果你们要找的是精神之石
then you've come to the right place.
那你们就来对地方了
We have it here.
你要找的东西就在这里
Or we did...once...maybe.
可能...曾经...大概
I'm afraid our memory is
not as great as our size.
恐怕我们的记忆不像我们的体形一样大
But, please, feel free
to have a look around.
不过请随意在这里寻找吧
No, no. Not with those eyes.
不，不是用肉眼去找
With that one.
用那个
Yes, I can sense its power.
没错，我能感觉到他的力量
Come with me.
跟我来
That's a lot of food, Aburn.
食物可真多啊，Aburn.
It's the harvest, and we
must move it to safekeeping.
现在是丰收时节，我们得把食物妥善保护起来
Safekeeping from what?
为了防止什么?
I...don't remember.
我...也不太清楚
Of course you don't.
好吧，你果然不知道
Like I told you,
I've already tried this.
我告诉过你，我已经这么试过了
The sword only shows me
the stone, not where it is.
这把剑只显示出石头的影像，没有显示出它到底在哪
Because you are not in
harmony with your sword.
那是因为你没有和剑融为一致
It is more than a tool, Lion-O.
剑不仅仅是一个工具，狮猫
It is a part of you.
它是你的一部分
Try again.
再试试
Sword of Omens...
神秘之剑...
Give me Sight Beyond Sight.
让我视他人之所不能
I can't concentrate with
all that noise. What is it?
那些噪音让我分神，到底是什么？
The Wraiths! They come from
the hills for the harvest!
是猎食蜂，他们被丰收吸引来的
Whiskers.
麻烦了
Why are they just sitting there?
他们怎么坐在那一动不动
I think they're meditating.
我觉得他们在冥想
Aren't you gonna do anything?
你不准备做点什么吗？
But we are.
我们在做啊
We are understanding.
我们在试着理解
Well, the Thundercats handle
things a little differently.
好吧，不过霹雳猫可不会这么处理问题
Thundercats...ho!
霹雳猫 吼
Hyah!
喝呀！
Have them on the run now.
已经把他们赶跑了
Yeah, but they got what they came for.
不过他们已经拿到想要的东西了
They wiped out your harvest.
他们抢走了你们收获的果实
They took most of our
food, but not all of our food.
他们是拿走了很多，不过不是全部
We still have enough to survive.
我们是还有足够的食物生活的
In order to get the
water it needs to thrive,
为了获得生长所需的水分
this fruit suffers the storms.
这些果实经受了暴风雨
We, too, must endure hardships to live.
我们也一样，生命中总是要忍受艰苦
Such is the balance of the world.
这就是自然的平衡
Remember, work in harmony with your sword.
记住，和你的剑融为一体
Allow the bigger picture to emerge.
开阔你的内心
Keep practicing.
继续练习
If he's not gonna do something
about the Wraiths, then I will.
如果他不准备对付猎食蜂的话，我来
Ooh.
哇
Huh?
哈？
That song you
are playing,
你们吹的曲子，
it's very sad.
很悲伤
It's a lullaby.
这是首摇篮曲
Our mother used to hum it to us.
妈妈曾经给我们唱过
While you miss her greatly,
看来你们真的很想念母亲
know she always lives
on through your song.
要知道她一直活在你们的歌中
Oh, but please, continue.
I didn't mean to interrupt.
哦，别停下，我不是有意要打断的
What just happened?
发生了什么？
It seems we achieved
perfect harmony--
好像我们达成了完美的和谐
a beautiful and powerful thing.
优美而强大的曲子
Wow.
哇哦
It's no wonder the elephants don't
do anything about these pests.
难怪那些大象不去对付这些蜂
It's too hard to get here.
要爬到这里太难了
Uh-oh. Here they come.
他们来了
Aah!
啊!
Uhh!
呃！
So that's where you're coming from.
原来这就是你们的老巢
Mind if I close the front door?
不介意我把洞口堵上吧？
Ho!
吼！
Aburn!
Aren't you supposed to
be practicing with Anet?
你不是应该和Anet在练习吗？
I thought I'd do you a favor instead.
我帮了你个忙
I took care of your Wraiths.
我收拾了那群猎食蜂
They won't be bothering you anymore.
它们不会再来打扰你了
Oh, you shouldn't have done that.
哦，你不应该那么做的
What? Why?
什么？为什么？
I don't remember...
我想不起来了...
But there's a good reason.
但一定有个理由的
Because the harmony of the universe
因为自然的协调
is now out of tune.
现在失衡了
You see, Lion-O,
正像你所说的，狮猫
the Wraiths may have
taken some of our crops,
猎食蜂的确抢走了我们的粮食
but their loud sounds were all that kept
但他们的噪音
something far worse away from our village.
让村庄免遭更可怕的东西侵袭
Without its natural
enemy patrolling the sky,
没有了它的天敌在天空中徘徊
this creature will do worse
than just eat our food.
那个生物会来村子里造成更大的毁坏
I didn't know.
我并不知道...
We elephants may not remember much,
我们大象没法记住很多东西
but we never forget there is a
delicate balance to all things.
但我们知道世间万物都有微妙的平衡
Come, let us meditate.
来吧，我们冥想
Come on. We can't wait
for it to come to us.
我们可不能让那东西爬上来
It'll destroy the entire village.
它会把整个村子都毁掉
Where are you going?
你去哪？
To meditate.
去冥想
Thundercats...ho!
霹雳猫 吼
Hyah!
哈呀！
What should we do?
我们该怎么办
Simply let the answer come to you.
让答案来找你就行了
Lovely harmony, sis.
美妙的和谐
You see, Lion-O,
你明白了吗，狮猫
when you fail to look
at the bigger picture,
当你没有纵观大局开阔思想
it becomes impossible to know
the consequences of your actions.
你就不能知道你行为的后果
I guess it's no wonder why I'm
struggling with Sight Beyond Sight.
我想我知道为什么我没法看到石头的所在了
Let's try it one more time.
再试一次
Sword of Omens, give
me Sight Beyond Sight.
神秘之剑，让我视他人所不能
The hut. The stone is in the hut!
是小屋，石头在那间屋子里
I don't understand.
我不明白
Perhaps a different
approach is in order.
也许这是寻找石头必经之路
Go to the forest of Magi Orr
去玛格奥尔森林
one of the most enchanted
places on all of Third Earth.
那是第三地球上魔法气息最浓郁的地方
There the power of the
sword will be amplified,
在哪里剑能力量会增强
and your connection with it.
你和剑的联系也会随之增强
Where is this forest?
那个森林在哪里？
Um, isn't it...?
呃，好像是...
Um, uh...
嗯...呃...
I was just there.
我才去过那里.
Let me think.
让我想一想.
Oh, brother.
哦，伙计们.